so here I'm going to roll through a few
different hip thrust strategies with you
so this here is a Max single with 675
lbs so many people would say wow Brett
good job you got it but let me play it
in slow motion here I do not achieve
full hip extension at the top see how
high my chest is and my hips are dropped
I have anterior pelvic tilt I don't feel
any tension on my glutes girl put a
picture a a freeze shot that is not a
good lockout right there and because of
that I didn't feel much tension on my
glutes so I went too heavy now here's
the second option and this is High Reps
with lightweight so here I do 245 lb for
25 reps now the interesting thing about
this is the first 15 reps I didn't
really feel anything it was so easy I'm
just pumping them out but the last 10
reps is when I start to feel a lot of
burn in my glutes and uh this is like
all metabolic stress not this isn't high
tension this is mostly you know High
metabolic stress
you do get high activation at the end
but you don't feel in your glutes as
much so look at my face there you can
see big burn in the
glutes now here's a third option
here and this is a 585 lb uh set for
five reps now here I do achieve lock out
I get five reps but this is a better
weight cuz I am locking out and I'm
getting full hip extension so I do feel
my glutes at the end of this set so you
don't go too heavy to where you can
achieve a good lockout but my favorite
option is band hip thrust and I like
doing these for sets of around 15 reps
is I think the best sweet spot because
at the top you can see here how I get
full hip extension at the top with a
some posterior pelvic tilt I squeeze the
glutes up top very high tension but you
also feel a huge burn so you get the
best of both worlds metabolic stress and
tension